-早啊宝贝 早饭就快好了 -早
- Hi honey, breakfast will be ready in a minute. - Hi.
我的手-手-手
My ha-a-a-nd!
好好笑哦 老妈
Very funny, mom.
我知道今天是万圣节啦
I know it's Halloween.
假手挺逼真啊
Nice fake hand.
我们超爱万圣节
We love Halloween.
尤其是克莱尔
Especially Claire.
我最爱的节日 没有之一
It's my favorite holiday.
从小我就喜欢惊悚恐怖的东东
Ever since I was a kid, I loved scary things.
每次新上一部恐怖片
If there was a new horror movie in town,
我肯定第一个去排队
I was the first in line.
"一张票 谢谢"
"One, please."
后来我遇到了菲尔
Then I met Phil.
"两张票 谢谢"
"Two, please."
好了
Okay.
搞定 帮我拉一下
All right. Do me.
拉呀 拉呀 拉呀
Do me, do me, do me.
小卡 我得说 我穿这个还挺性感
Cam, I have to say, I feel kind of sexy.
性感得吱吱直响 但...
Well, squeaky sexy, but...
你知道 如果不是这么讨厌万圣节
You know I'd be enjoying this more
我觉得老公穿成这样儿也挺好的
if Halloween wasn't such a tough day for me.
但我想你打扮停当去上班
But I want you to go to work...
让他们羡慕嫉妒恨
and knock their socks off.
之前我一直在一间古板保守的律所工作
Well, my last job was at a pretty conservative law firm.
没有人会在万圣节装扮自己
No one there would ever dress up for Halloween.
但很明显现在这间律所...
But apparently at this new company...
呃 我在想是扮成吸血鬼呢 还是狼人呢
Um, right now I'm thinking either vampire or werewolf.
每年都让我很伤脑筋啊
Every year it's harder to decide.
等一下 等一下 不好意思
Wait, wait, wait. I-I'm sorry.
等等 请问你们真的穿着戏服来上班吗
Wait. So people really come to work in costumes here?
开玩笑吗 这可是传统啊伙计
Are you kidding? It's epic, bro!
传统
Epic.
我是新来的
I'm already the new guy.
我可不想和大伙儿格格不入
I don't want to be the nonpartipation guy, too.
有我在就不会
Not on my watch.
不幸的是 我对万圣节的爱在很久之前
Unfortunately, Halloween was marred for me personally
就因为某件事戛然而止了
by an incident long ago.
现在能撑过这一天我都觉得命大
Now it's just a day I have to get through.
你又来了
So you've said.
好了 大家下午五点半在这儿集合
All right, so, everybody has to be here at 5:30
为晚上的鬼屋活动做准备
to rehearse our house of horrors.
你们都准备好要打扮成什么了吗
You guys have your costumes ready?
好了 不过暂时保密
Yeah, but it's a secret.
我和曼尼一起弄的
Me and Manny came up with something together.
太棒了
I love that!
-我现在能吃点糖吗 -不行
- Can I have some candy? - No.
你呢 艾丽克斯
How 'bout you, Alex?
我没空考虑这个
Well, I haven't really thought about it.
我明天有三门很重要的考试
I've got, like, three huge exams tomorrow.
宝贝 万圣节装扮可不能临时抱佛脚啊
Honey, you can't just slap something together at the last minute.
你知道吗 如果你能把花功课上的时间
You know, if you gave this costume half as much time
分一半给准备今晚的着装
and attention as you give your homework,
也不至于像现在这样儿
you wouldn't be in this situation.
提醒你一下 你有个孩子是读书天才哦
Can I remind you, you have one child who's not mediocre?
这身怎么样 恐怖猫女装
Check it. I'm a scary black cat.
吓不倒别人 倒是把我吓得心肝乱颤
The only person that costume scares is me.
-去换一身 -换成什么
- Go change it. - To what?
随便什么 你以前穿过的吧
I don't know. One of your old costumes.
宝贝 相信我
Honey, trust me.
如果不换的话 你一整天
I am sparing you an entire day
都会被男人问 你的舌头是否也如猫般有摩擦快感
of guys asking you if you have a rough tongue.
喂
Hello.
喂 爸 是我
Hi. Dad. It's me.
我就是问问你和歌洛莉亚准备好今晚活动了没
I wanted to make sure you and Gloria were ready for tonight.
-今晚什么活动 -你不会全忘光了吧
- What's tonight? - What do you mean, what is tonight?
爸 今晚万圣节啊 你知道的
Dad, it's Halloween. You know this.
别着急 莫蒂莎 我逗你呢
Calm down, Morticia, I'm just teasing you.
晚上见
We'll be there.
好 但是要穿戏服来
Yeah, but in costume this time.
这次你不能再像去年那样反戴着棒球帽
You can't just show up with a backwards baseball cap
还自称是斯路普·道格[黑人嘻哈歌星]
and call yourself Snoop Dogg like you did last year.
我压根儿就不知道那人是谁
I didn't even know who that guy was.
是海莉把我帽子反过来还叫我这么说的
Haley turned my hat around and told me to say it.
我以为他是什么寻狗侦探呢
I thought he was a dog detective.
听着 别担心 我们已经准备好了
Listen, don't worry. We got the whole thing worked out.
拜拜
Bye-bye.
-哈啰 杰 -你在哪儿
- Hola, Jay! - Where are you?
我捎了曼尼和他同学一程
I have Manny in the carpool,
偶们就快到"辍学区"了
and we're going to the dropout.
辍学? 你是说那个叫埃迪的小孩吗
Dropout? You mean that Eddie kid?
他确实傻逼兮兮的
Yeah, he's a moron.
不是啦
No, the dropout,
就是学校里让孩子们下车的地儿
where you drop the kids in the school.
她意思是"下客区"
She means "Drop-off."
偶就是这么说滴呀
That's what I said.
听着 你准备好今晚
Listen, did you ever do anything about costumes
克莱尔那活动要穿的了吗
for Claire's thing tonight?
偶下午就去取
I'm going to pick them up this afternoon.
你扮成"夜龙"
You're going to be a "Gargle,"
偶扮成邪恶村庄布鲁哈
and I'm gonna be an evil village bruja.
你越说我越糊涂
I know less now than I did before I asked.
布鲁哈就是巫婆 夜龙就是夜龙嘛
Hmm. A bruja is a witch, and a gargle is a gargle.
她是在说夜行神龙
She means "Gargoyle."
我就是这么说的
That's what I said.
你有所准备就好
As long as you got it covered.
要是达不到克莱尔想要的效果
Because if Claire doesn't get her Halloween,
她就会变成现实版的巫婆
she turns into a real "Rhymes with 'bruja.'"
哦 不 就我一个穿了
Oh, no. No, no, no. I'm the only one.
吃午饭的时候 我会让你戴我的獠牙的
At lunch, I'll let you wear my fangs.
看看这些傻子
Look at those tools.
每年都这样 真是一对蠢蛋
Every year. What a couple of douches.
噢 不
Ohh. Oh, no.
喂
Hello?
只有三个人穿着戏服
There are exactly three people in costume here -
一个傻瓜 一个蠢蛋 还有一个我
A tool, a douche, and me.
可我现在没有时间回家来换衣服了
And I don't have time to go home and change and -
冷静
Calm down.
你带了昨天要送去干洗的衣服了吗
Did you bring in the dry-cleaning from last night?
你是不是想用这个来惹我生气
Are you really getting on me about the dry-cleaning wh-
噢 对了 后备箱里有套西装
Oh. I have suits in the trunk.
看吧 懒人有懒福
Look at that. Yesterday's lazy cures today'crazy.
好样的 感谢上帝
Yes. Thank you! Thank you.
这就去换
Okay.
噢终于找到你了
Oh, there you are.
我需要你去开兰普金的会
Hey, I need you in the Lampkin meeting.
-等不能等我先... -只要5分钟
-If I could just maybe have -Five minutes.
好吧
O-kay.
-问你个法律问题 -什么
-Okay, hey. First legal question. -Yeah?
我能平白无故地炒了这俩笨蛋吗
Can I fire those idiots for no reason?
上帝啊
Oh, my gosh.
-你手臂可真壮实 -额 是的
-Those are some major guns you got there. -Eh, yeah.
这东西怎么...
Why won't this...
嗨 杰瑞
Hey, Jerry.
嗨 菲尔 装扮得不错
Hey, Phil. Looking good.
谢谢 看到我们今晚的准备你会更吃惊
Thanks. Wait till you see what we got planned for tonight.
克莱尔和我准备扮成僵尸夫妇
Claire and I are going as corpse bride and groom.
好像夫妇都是行尸走肉吧
As if there's any other kind, am I right?
-我是说 婚姻让人好想死哦 -朱蒂把我甩了
-I'm saying marriage kills you. -Judy left me.
天呐
Oh, my god.
真为你遗憾
I am so sorry.
当你的同龄人奔赴黄泉的时候
When someone your age dies,
你最想知道什么
What's the first thing you want to know?
是怎么死的 对吧
"Died of what?" Right?
你希望死因是
You want to hear it was something
一件永远不会发生在你身上的事
That could never happen to you.
离婚也一样
Well, it's the same with divorce.
如果是因为 酗酒 出轨 虐待
Tell me it was booze, cheating, physical abuse.
没关系 我是个酒量一般 用情专一的好男人
No problem. I'm a monogamous social drinker,
克莱尔也只有睡着了偶尔踹我一脚
And Claire only sleep-hits me.
别告诉我就那么突然发生了
Just don't tell me it came from out of the blue.
我完全傻了眼
I was totally blindsided.
我想这一路走来
I guess somewhere along the way
她发现我不再讨人喜欢了
She stopped finding me delightful.
那完全就是胡扯
Well, that's - that's coconuts.
你超级讨人喜欢
You're super delightful.
但对朱蒂来说不再是了
Not to Judy.
她以前都会因为我的一举一动而大笑
She used to laugh at everything I had to say,
但现在我都记不清她的笑声是什么样的了
But now I can't even remember what her laugh sounds like.
克莱尔会模仿 简直惟妙...
Claire can do it. It's uncan-
我差不多该回家了
I should go back inside.
我还有碗要洗
I have a dish to wash.
好吧 但是
Okay, but, hey...
杰瑞 你有什么需要就来找我
Jerry, if you need anything, all right?
我是你坚强的后盾
I'm your rock.
你一定会觉得难以置信
You are not gonna believe this.
朱蒂和杰瑞离婚了
Judy just left Jerry.
想想也会 她这些日子都过的不开心
Oh, yeah. She was so unhappy.
他怎么样了
How's he doing?
他可不像你这么轻松地就接受了
He's not taking it as well as you are.
抱歉 亲爱的 不是我麻木不仁
Oh, I'm sorry, honey. I don't mean to be insensitive.
只是我现在太忙了
I've just got a lot to get done.
我没有觉得你麻木不仁 我觉得你很讨喜
I don't find you insensitive. I find you delightful.
你觉得我讨喜吗
Do you find me delightful?
噢 天呐 我差点忘了
Oh, god, I just remembered!
杰瑞本应扮演我们走廊处的稻草人的
Jerry's supposed to be our porch scarecrow.
你能请他继续来吗
Can you ask him if he'll still do it?
他现在心情很糟糕
He's kind of a mess right now.
我知道 可有人陪着总归比较好
Yeah, but it might make him feel better be around people.
我去试试
I'll try...
不过他的世界刚刚天翻地覆
But his whole world just turned upside down.
你能想象有多糟糕吗
Can you imagine?
前一分钟还夫妻恩爱
One minute, you're happily married,
下一分钟却劳燕分飞了
The next minute, you're completely by yourself.
你们别找借口了 我需要撤销这起诉讼
I don't need excuses. I need this lawsuit to go away.
谁负责凯瑟的证言
Now, who's responsible for the Keith deposition?
是我 "先僧"
uh, well, I was, "Shir."
但我要为自己辩解一下 有人"告树"我
But, uh, in my defense, I "Wash" told
脱下你那愚蠢的獠牙 戴尔
Take those stupid fangs out, Dale.
首先 现在是白天
For starters, it's daytime.
吸血鬼白天都在睡大觉
Vampires sleep during the day...
如果你不幸被炒 就可以睡个够了
which you may soon have plenty of time for.
真抱歉 但是有人跟我说我们不需要凯瑟了
I'm sorry, but I was told that we didn't need Keith.
谁告诉你的
Who told you that?
是是是 我说的 老大
I-I-I may have. I may have done that, sir.
真令人失望
Well, that's disappointing.
但是米奇尔初来乍到
But at least Mitchell's new here.
暮光哥 你是老员工了
Twilight, you're not.
赶紧去办 散会
So get it done. Meeting adjourned.
客户还在我办公室等着呢 我们要迟到了
Client's waiting for us in my office. We're already late.
-哦 -赶紧走
-Ohh. -Let's roll.
-啊 你健身效果不错啊 -是的
-Ah, you've really been hitting the gym. -Yeah.
那到底是什么声音
What the hell is that noise?
每次我想脱掉那戏服的时候
Every time I tried to get out of that costume,
就有人拉我去开会
I got dragged into another meeting.
简直是有史以来最糗的万圣节
It was the worst Halloween ever.
是吗 米奇尔 真的是最糗的吗
Really, Mitchell? The worst Halloween ever?
你不过只是大腿咯吱作响
You had squeaky thighs.
我的童年却毁于一旦
I lost a childhood.
杰 有你的包裹
Jay! This came for you.
哦 亲爱的 是什么呢
Oh. Hi, honey. What is it?
我打电话叫你的秘书
I called your secretary and told her
订了一些薄脆饼干
to order you some crackers
还有你喜欢的奶酪
and those cheeses that you like -
就是小小的那种
the tiny, little ones.
谢谢 你取回我的"夜龙"戏服了嘛
Thanks. Did you pick up my "Gargle" Costume, too?
-你在取笑我吗 -没有啊
-Are you making fun of me? -No.
先是曼尼纠正我发音 现在又轮到你
First, Manny correcting me. And now you?
要是我有问题 杰 我愿意洗耳恭听
If I have a problem, I want to know, Jay.
听着 亲爱的 英语是你的第二语言
Honey, look, English is your second language.
你已经说得很好了
You're doing great.
你这样估计我滴感受 不利于我滴进步
Yeah, you're not helping by protecting my feelings.
我要你实话实说
I want you to be honest with me.
好吧 我察觉到了一些微不足道的错误
Okay, well, I may have noticed some tiny, little mistakes
你可能要注意一下
you might want to take a look at.
-比如说 -就是一些发音错误 比如说
-Like what? -Just little mispronunciations. Like, for example
昨晚你说 "我们住在狗狗的世界里"
Last night, you said, "We live in a doggy-dog world."
-怎么了 -实际上应该是"狗咬狗的世界"
-So? -Well, it's "Dog-eat-dog world."
是啊 但是
Yeah, but...
这根本说不通啊
that doesn't make any sense.
谁想生活在一个狗互吃的世界啊
Who wants to live in a world where dogs eat each other?
狗狗的世界是漂亮滴世界
A doggy-dog world is a beautiful world
狗狗到处都是
full of little puppies!
我还说错什么了
What else do I say wrong?
还有 不是"天上来的祝福"
Well, it's not "Blessings in the skies."
而是"因祸得福"
It's "Blessings in disguise."
还有呢
What else?
是"腕管综合症"
"Carpal tunnel syndrome"
不是"拼车管综合症"
is not "Carpool tunnel syndrome."
还有呢
And what else?
"型感的"也不对
It's not "Volumptuous."
好了对了 我知道我口音很重
Okay, enough. I know that I have an accent.
但是大家都能听懂
But people understand me just fine!
这到底是啥
What the hell is this?
我跟你说了 杰 我打电话给你的秘书
I told you, Jay, I called your secretary
叫她给你订一盒小奶酪
and told her to order you a box of baby cheeses.
哦 这次又是我滴错了
Oh, so now that is my fault too.
好吧 能否转达克莱尔
Oh, yeah, can you tell Claire
我不大想来扮演稻草人
that I'm not really up for being the scarecrow?
我和朱蒂以前很爱万圣节
Judy and I used to love Halloween.
这是她最喜欢的节日
It's her favorite holiday.
-啊哈 -你懂吧
-Huh. -You know?
天啊 想到你一个人坐在家里胡思乱想
Gosh, I hate to think of you sitting in there alone,
我就觉得于心不忍
running through all this in your head.
你表现得再好也于事无补啊
What could you have done differently?
我真的觉得难以启齿
It's actually a little hard for me to talk about.
别对我紧闭心扉嘛 人家又不是朱蒂
Don't push me away. I'm not Judy.
我要是再随意自然一些就好了
I could've been more spontaneous.
我要是能更加幽默性感就好了
I-I-I could've tried to have been more fun and sexy
就像过去一样
like I was in the old days.
随意自然 性感诱惑 我懂了 懂了
Spontaneous and sexy. I got it. Yep.
记住了 有事随时找我 好吗
And remember, I'm here for you, okay?
哦哦哦 我擦
Ohh! Son of a...
你穿的是啥
What the hell is that?!
怎么了 你叫我穿以前的戏服
What? You told me to put on an old costume.
你也不能穿8岁那套啊
Not from when you were 8.
你是想别人给你糖果 还是要吸引日本怪叔叔
Are you trying to get candy or Japanese businessmen?
换了 快去
Change it. Go.
杰瑞不能扮演稻草人了
Jerry is a no-go on the crow.
你在他那儿待了这么久吗
You've been over there this whole time?
对啊 他一直倾诉 我不忍心丢下他一个人
Yeah, he was venting. I couldn't break free.
老天
God...
你真是秀色可餐
You are sexy.
亲爱的
Honey...
别啊 还没完呢 亲爱的
Not so fast. I don't think we're done here, my darling.
别闹了 我要下来
It's okay. I need to get down.
噢 要下面吗 我可以一直往下哦
Oh, we can get down. We can get way down.
天啊
Oh, god!
菲尔
Phil!
别 不要 不要 不要
No! No, no, no, no, no! No!
好吧
Okay.
不会吧
Oh, no.
别别别别 好吧
No, no, no, no, no, no, no. Okay.
好吧 淡定 米奇尔 淡定淡定
Okay. Focus, Mitchell. Focus. Focus.
喂
Hello?
我困在男厕所了
I'm trapped in a men's room,
身上唯一的衣服就是蜘蛛侠装了
And all I have on is the spider-man suit.
真够火辣的 请问你是哪位
Hot. Who is this?
有人把我衬衣拿走了 我剩下的衣服
Somebody took my shirt, and all the rest
都浸在坐便池里了
of my clothes are all "Toilety."
我完蛋了
I'm screwed.
你干嘛不跟查理实话实说呢
Why don't you just tell Charlie the truth?
我不能 我今天已经搞砸一次了
I can't. I already messed up once today.
我可不能冒这个险
And I can't risk it.
我后备箱里还有一套西装
I-I have another suit in my trunk,
但我要到达停车位 就必须穿过办公室
But I can't get to the car without going through the office.
你知道最讽刺的是什么吗
You know what's ironic?
现在真正能帮你的
Who could really help you right now
就是蜘蛛侠了
is spider-man.
蜘蛛侠来也！
He's here.
好了 好了 好了
Okay. Okay. Okay.
不
No.
别叫 别叫 别叫 别叫
No, no, no, no, no, no.
别叫 别叫 别叫
No, no, no.
好吧 好吧
Um, o-okay. Okay.
看啊 我的子民
Behold, my creation.
怪物 听我指挥
Monster, do my bidding!
谨遵命令 主人
I do as you command, master.
好了 老妈
Okay. Mom.
千万别再不满意这件了
You cannot have a problem with this.
我是特雷莎修女
I'm mother Teresa.
你开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
怎么了 我是她热辣版的复活造型
What? I'm her back when she was hot.
你要再多穿点的话 我会给你10美元
I will pay you $10 to go put on more clothes.
此等待遇可是头一次哦
Bet it's the first time you ever heard that one.
好吧 知道吗 这儿 披上这个
Okay. You know what? Here. Here we go.
来帮你遮上点
Let's just cover you up.
好了 我想赶紧彩排一下
All right, now, I just want to run through this,
大家都快一点
really quick with everybody.
首先是 不给糖就捣蛋
Um, first, it's "Trick or treat?"
然后 菲尔
And then, Phil...
-有种就进来 -没错 然后老爸就
- "Come in if you dare." - Right, and then dad does
弄出电闪雷鸣的效果 还要放雾
the thunder and the lightning and the fog.
指导孩子们进来 经过装着艾丽克斯的笼子
Usher the children in past Alex in her cage.
-我被关在笼子里吗 -是的
- I'm in a cage? - Yes!
你被强行关押在一个鬼屋里
You're in a house of horrors being held against your will.
我知道 但要笼子干嘛
Yeah,I know, so why do we need the cage?
接着歌洛莉亚突然出现
And then Gloria pops up
就像乡村恶巫婆一样 然后她说
as the evil village bruja, and she says,
欢迎来到你的噩梦之境
"Welcome to your nightmare.
哈哈哈哈
Ah ha ha ha ha!"
然后小卡和海莉负责他们的部分
and the Cam and Haley do their thing.
小孩负责发糖 领他们出去
Kids get their candy. They are ushered out.
他们以后到此为止了 其实还没有
They think it's all over, but it's not!
因为在外面的走廊上
Because out on the porch,
稻草人会突然跳出来
the scarecrow pops to life.
然后就听到他们最后的一声惨叫
Wow! For one final "Aah!"
米奇尔 你扮演稻草人
And that's - Mitchell, you're the srecrow!
不要 不要
Oh, no, no.
我穿了一天的戏服 好想死啊
I was in a costume all day. It was awful.
这跟我当年根本没法比
It's nothing compared to when I was
-你没经历过糟糕的万圣节 -我没有
- You don't own bad halloweens. - Don't I?
我们懂的 小卡 伤心往事
We get it, Cam. Hard day.
米奇尔 拜托了 戏服就在厨房里
Mitchell, please. The costume's in the kitchen.
快点来嘛
Come on.
好了 克莱尔 克莱尔
All right, Claire, Claire.
在你离开我之前 我只想让你知道
Before you go, I just want you to know...
好的 我的假发 快掉了
Okay. The wig. That, that's...
我爱你胜过
I love you more...
嘴真甜 谢谢你 亲爱的
That's nice. Thanks, honey.
你是我最好的朋友
You're my best friend!
-大家好啊 -你来啦
- Hey, guys. - Hey.
天啊 你们俩看起来好极了
Wow. God, you guys look great.
谢谢你 菲尔 我尽力了
Thank you, Phil. I try my best.
你看起来非常像死人
You look very dead-like.
歌洛莉亚 别说了 我说过对不起了
Gloria, stop it. I said I was sorry.
不不 杰
Oh, no, no, Jay.
从现在起 我只说标准美式英语
For now on, I only speak in proper american,
这样我就不会使你丢人了
so I don't embarrass you.
她刚看完牙回来吗
Did she just get back from the dentist?
她在跟我发脾气 因为我跟她说
She's mad at me because I told her
有时候别人听不懂她在说什么
sometimes people can't understand her.
赶紧去弥补一下吧 杰
Make it right, Jay.
咱俩现在都岌岌可危了
We're all just hanging by a thread.
老爸 你看起来棒极了
Hey! Dad! Oh, you look great!
不错 好了 歌洛莉亚已经就位了
Oh, good. Okay, Gloria's in position.
你好 歌洛莉亚 就是这样
Hi, Gloria. There you go.
你就呆这儿
Right back here.
克莱尔 我不知道自己能否胜任这活
Claire, I don't know that I'm - I'm feeling up to this.
为什么 小卡 为什么呢
Why, Cam? Why?
到底发生了什么事
What happened that is so awful
糟糕到你都不敢告诉我们
you simultaneously can't speak of it
同时却又不住地提起呢
and yet can't stop talking about it?
说不出口 太伤感了
I can't. It's too emotional.
好吧 那下次吧
Okay. Some other time.
-我那时十岁 -天啊
- I was 10. - Oh, god.
跟我的好朋友迪米·瑞格纳一起
Dressed as Quasimodo on a front porch
他扮捉鬼人 我扮敲钟人[巴黎圣母院]
with my best friend, Timmy Reglar, a ghostbuster.
门廊上有一篮糖果 里面还有一张纸条
There was a bucket of candy with a sign.
-上面写着"拿一颗" -一颗
- It said "Take one." - One.
迪米把整篮糖都拿走放到了包里
Timmy took the entire bucket and put it in his bag.
迪米不守规矩
Timmy didn't play by the rules.
这正是我对他又爱又怕的地方
It's what I liked and feared about him.
然后包破了 正好一群小孩走过来
Then the bag broke as a crowd of kids
看到了地上掉的一堆糖
rounded the corner, saw the pile of candy.
迪米说 是小卡拿的
Timmy said, "Cam did it!"
-不给糖就捣蛋 -太好了
- Trick or treat? - Oh, good.
讲出来舒服多了吧
Aren't you glad yo got that out?
好了 大伙 这是我们第一批受害者
Okay, everybody, our first victims!
这可不是彩排咯 准备好了吗
This is not a rehearsal. You ready? You ready?
-好了 好了 -那就好
- Yes. Yes. - Okay.
有种的话就进来吧
Come in...if you dare.
爸
Dad.
等一下
Huh? Oh. L-let me see.
谢谢你们来参加
Thank you for joining us on our sp-
不 不 先要有雷鸣闪电
No, no, no. First the thunder and the lightning!
好的 就来
Yeah, right. I got it.
要命了
Perfect.
谢谢你们
Thank you for joining us...
参与我们的特别之夜
on our special night.
其他小孩的下场可不怎么样
Other children haven't fared so well.
欢迎来到你们的噩梦
Welcome to your nightmare. Ha ha ha ha!
那是怎么回事
What the hell is that?
能不能 直接把糖给我们
Can, uh -- can we just get our candy?
好的 但是小心有雾
OK, but beware of the fog,
因为你们可能看不清前
for you may not be able to see...
头
"ahead."
然后迪米就开始跑
Boop. Timmy started running.
我也想跑的
I wanted to run too,
可是我的肥肉被玫瑰花丛缠住了
but my hunch got stuck on a rose bush
所以我就摔倒了
and that's when I fell.
狠狠地摔了一跤
I fell hard.
我看得到他的脚
I can see his feet.
好吧 给 孩子们 拿点糖
Okay. Here, children, have some candy.
万圣节快乐
Happy Halloween.
好吧 刚才真烂 开局不利
Ok. That was bad. That was a bad start.
首先 爸 雷鸣闪电 然后放雾
Er... First of all, dad, thunder, lightening, fog cue.
然后我们一起转向艾丽克斯
And we skip Alex all together.
歌洛莉亚 你什么时候开始说英语了
And...Gloria, since when do you speak English?
你现在也开始不爽我的口音了
Oh, so now you have a problem with the way I speak?
有其父必有其女 真是个狗咬狗的家庭
Like father like daughter. In this dog-eat-dog family.
不给糖就捣乱
Trick or treat?
好了 各就各位 各就各位
Okay. Places, places.
很好 米奇尔也不见了
Good, Mitchell's gone.
亲爱的 我好爱你
Honey, I love you so much!
不是时候 不是时候
Not now, not now.
有种的话就进来吧
Come in...if you dare.
-爸 爸 -什么 对了 对了
- Dad. Dad. - What? Oh, right, right.
-菲尔到你了 -不对 爸 雾
- Phil, it's you. - No, dad, fog, fog.
感谢你们来参加
Thank you for joining us...
我们的特别之夜
on our special night.
其他小孩的下场可不怎么样
Other children haven't fared so well.
救救我 救救我
Oh, help me, help me.
欢迎来到你们的噩梦
Welcome to your nightmare. Ha ha ha ha.
你们的糖在这里
Now your treats are over here
但是雾这么大
but with all the fog
你们可能看不清前
you may not be able to see
头
"ahead".
然后大家都在喊
And everyone was screaming
就是他 抓住敲钟人
"That's him! Get Quasimodo!"
于是镇里人就开始追我
And then the townspeople started chasing me!
然后我就尿裤子了
And that's when I wet my pants!
我尿裤子了 我尿裤子了
I wet my pants! I wet my pants.
这地方好诡异 我们走
This place is weird. Let's go.
圣母玛利亚
Mother of god.
混账东西
Ohh! Son of a...
你们到底是怎么回事
What is wrong with everyone?!
小卡 "镇里人" 你在说什么
Cam, "townspeople"? Really?
我住在农场 他们住在镇里
I lived on a farm. They lived in town.
他们就是镇里人
They were the townspeople.
还有爸 爸
And, dad! Dad!
应该是 闪电 雷鸣 放雾
It goes -- lightning, thunder, fog cue!
这整件事就够雾蒙蒙的了
This whole thing is a colossal fog cue.
克莱尔不会明白的 小卡
Claire just doesn't understand, Cam.
也许她从来没有因与众不同而被欺负
Maybe she's never been picked on for being different.
你有吗 歌洛莉亚
When, Gloria?
你什么时候因为
When have you ever been picked on
"与众不同"而被欺负过
for "being different"?
问问"夜龙"就知道了
Ask the "Gargle."
她在说什么
What did she say?
歌洛莉亚
Gloria!
我觉得她疯了
I think she went insane.
她没疯 她是我妈
She's not insane. She's my mother.
我现在才是你妈
I'm your mother now!
歌洛莉亚
Gloria...
我想给你讲个故事
I want to tell you a story...
一个男人独自在餐厅吃饭
about a guy eating in a diner, alone.
他听到身后有一个女人在讲话
Behind him he hears a woman talking.
他一直没有转过身来 五分钟过了 十分钟过了
He doesn't turn around, 5 minutes, 10 minutes.
他只是静静地聆听着那位女士
Just listening to the woman,
听她声音中的生命力
the life in her voice.
他还未与她谋面
And before he even sees her
就爱她爱得无法自拔
He realizes he's fallen in love.
现在 我想让你猜猜那个男人是谁
Now, I'll give you a guess who that guy is.
我爸好
Aw, my dad was --
我的天啊
Oh, my god!
你知道吗 我打算现在就走了
You know what? I'm just gonna go.
别啊 小卡 别这样
No. Come on, Cam.
要是小卡舅夫要走
Uh, if uncle Cam is leaving,
那我也要回楼上读书去了
I'm just gonna go upstairs and study.
我还要去赶个派对 所以
Yeah, I have a party to go to, so...
她往我脸上挥了一拳
Ohh! She punched me in the face!
他不知从哪里突然冒出来
He came out of nowhere, and he scared
把老娘吓的魂都没了
the baby "cheeses" out of me!
你开始像平常一样的说话了
Hey, you're talking normal again.
我好爱那个老男人的故事
Oh, I loved the story about the old man.
我可没说"老"这个字
Well, nobody said "old".
-小卡 我们可以走了吗 -可以
- Oh, Cam, can we please just go? - Yes.
好 求你们了 都走吧 我才不在乎呢
Yeah, go, please. I don't care.
克莱尔
Oh, Claire.
没事 没事
No, no.
都完了 到此为止吧
I'm done. I'm done.
还没 我压根就还没说完呢 你们自己想想
I'm not done. So not done. Look, here's the thing.
我们 我们现在圣诞节放烟火
We - we have reworks at Christmas now
因为那是哥伦比亚人的过节方式 我能接受
because that's what they do in Colombia, and I don't mind.
感恩节 以前都是由我来给大家烤火鸡
Thanksgiving - that used to be me roasting a turkey,
直到同性恋夫夫把这活拿走了
until the gays took it over
然后用按他们在美食频道看的最新潮的
with whatever new turkey-cooking craze it is
火鸡料理方法来料理
that you saw on the Food Network.
我也一样没意见
And, I'm fine with that too.
我只求 我只求你们能把万圣节留给我
All I ask - all I ask is that you leave me Halloween.
没错 万圣节
Yeah, Halloween.
我知道这是个疯狂的节日
I realize it is a crazy-ass holiday
疯狂到可以让一个中年熟女如此在乎
for a grown woman to care about this much.
但那就是属于我的疯狂节日
But it is my crazy-ass holiday.
我的
Mine.
她还真是一肚子怨气啊
That's a lot of complaining from somebody
去年我们做的火鸡 她要了三次呢
who asked for thirds of our tandoori turkey last year.
克莱尔
Claire.
不想 不想 我现在不想说话
No! No! Not ready to talk!
不想
No.
你听我说
Listen...
我知道我今天没怎么帮到忙
I know I haven't been much help today.
但那 那杰瑞跟朱蒂的事情
That - that whole Jerry and Judy thing,
真的让我心不在焉
it really hit me hard.
你一整天疯疯癫癫的就是为这破事吗
Is that why you've been acting like such a nut all day?
-万一有天那发生在我们身上怎么办 -宝贝
- You know, what if someday that's us? - Honey!
好吧 你 你现在可能不会想听到这个
Okay, you - you might not want to hear this right now
因为我刚刚在里面大发了脾气 但是
after the meltdown I just had in there, but...
你休想逃出我的手掌心
you're kind of stuck with me.
你保证吗
You promise?
我愿意
I do.
真好
Oh. That's great.
不给糖 就捣蛋
Trick or treat?
我们应该就放一大碗的糖果
We should just put out a bowl of candy
然后一起喝杯鸡尾酒 对吧
and have a cocktail, right?
-对的 -好吧
-Yeah. -Yeah.
有种的话就进来吧
Come in if you dare.
谢谢你们来参加我们的特别之夜
thank you for joining us on our special night.
其他小孩的下场可不怎么样
Other children haven't fared so well.
-救救我 救救我 -她们真的在演
-Help me! Help me! -She's doing it.
-欢迎来到你们的恶梦 孩子们 -不要 不要
- Welcome to your nightmare, muchachos! - No!no!
但是雾这么大 你们可能看不清前 头
But with all this fog, it might be hard to see "ahead."
-棒啊 -好啊
-Yeah! -Yeah!
我们回来参与了 走吧
We're back in the game! Let's go!
我爱死了 我爱死这个了
I love it! I love it!
特别为你弄的
Whoa! That was for you.
-特别为你触发的 我为了你弄的 -你才不是呢
-That was for you. I just did it for you. -No, it wasn't.
有一次她说 别开玩笑
Oh, and one time she says don't joke
别逼老娘对你不仁不"腻"
or I'll have to give you the "Hindenburg maneuver".
有一次 她发现我在放空
Oh, one time she caught me staring off.
她就说 小卡 怎么了
And she goes, "Cam, what's wrong?
你看起来像有头虱的鹿[鹿灯综合症]
You look like a deer in head lice!".
当兵那会 我有个工作 基本上就是
In the service, I had a job, briefly,
处理炸药
handling explosives.
听起来很危险 其实不然
Which sounds dangerous, but it's not.
你把它们存放在适宜的温度之下
You store them at the right temperature,
就不会有任何危险
you have no problems...
要是你告诉她 她别无选择
If you tell her she doesn't have a choice,
她会说 别给我个老番茄[最后通牒ultimatum]
She'll say, "don't you give me an 'old tomato.'"
-或者当她说 -好了 够了
- Or when she says - Okay! Enough!
你们试试说外语
You try speaking in another language!
所有人滚出我家
Everybody out of my house!
直到忽然爆发
...until you do.